Wen Dong

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wen-dong-windsor • https://github.com/fanchuanster 401 Sunset Avenue, Windsor, Ontario N9B 3P4, +16476962130 • dong23@uwindsor.ca

May 14, 2021

CIBC, Toronto-33 Yonge Street, 7th

Re: Data Scientist Co-op

Dear Recruiter at CIBC:

Being immersed in the software development industry for more than ten years, with substantial interest in software design and data analysis, I was inspired to pursue graduate level Computing Science study, I hope to apply my experience and skills as a Data Scientist Coop to support CIBC's needs as I value your innovation-focused and diverse culture, admire your distinguished reputation and relate to your vision to enhance client experience and change the way that people bank.

Working as a Software Developer and later as a SaaS System Engineer in Micro Focus, I developed and advanced skills in Python/C++, and Cloud Computing, and consolidated skills on software design and programming.

Apart from employment experience, during my Master of Applied Computing program in University of Windsor, I learned hard on data analysis – Deep learning and Machine learning in the hope of shifting to this amazing and interesting arena, and successfully completed two relevant academic projects with TensorFlow, Keras, Neural Network, MongoDB, ex cetera.

I sincerely appreciate the opportunity sharing more about my design, programming, and data analysis skills during an interview with you. Thank you for your time reviewing my application.

Best regards,

Wen Dong

Wen Dong

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wen-dong-windsor • https://github.com/fanchuanster 401 Sunset Avenue, Windsor, Ontario N9B 3P4, +16476962130 • dong23@uwindsor.ca

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C/C++/C#, Java, Bash, Ansible, PowerShell
- Software Tools: Git, Visual Studio, Eclipse, UML Tool, Tableau, PyCharm
- Framework & Libraries: TensorFlow/Keras, Hadoop/Spark, Selenium, Jenkins, Docker
- Cloud Computing: AWS (Amazon Web Service), Google Cloud
- Database: MySQL, Oracle, MS SQL Server, PostgreSql, MongoDB, Neo4j

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Computing, University of Windsor, ON

Sep 2020 – present

- Relevant courses AI Introduction, Advanced Computing Concepts, Advanced Database,
 Advanced Software Engineering, Advanced System Programming
- Available for a 4-month internship starting from Sep 2021

Bachelor of Engineering, Wuhan University of Sci & Tech, Wuhan, China Sep 2002 – Jun 2006

- Major Computer Science and Technology
- Relevant courses Database, Data Structure, C Programming Language, Operating System

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Movie Recommendation (Team Project), University of Windsor, ON Technologies: Python/Flask, Angular

Oct 2020 – Dec 2021

 Built a movie recommendation system using Machine Learning algorithms like TFIDF, Linear Kernel from scikit-learn library

Diabetes Prediction System (Team Project), University of Windsor, ON Feb 2021 – Apr 2021 Technologies: TensorFlow/Keras, TensorBoard, Python, Google Cloud

- Created a Neural Network model by applying Deep Learning algorithms to diabetes dataset and deployed it to Google Cloud
- Visualized the training process with TensorBoard for debugging and performance tuning
- Improved the prediction accuracy from 60% to 87% with KarasTuner

WORK EXPERIENCE

SaaS System Engineer, SaaS Delivery BU, Micro Focus, Shanghai, China Technologies: Python, AWS, Ansible, Oracle DB, Docker

Sep 2019 – Present

- Designed and programmed to automate the deployment process of our Application Lifecycle Management system on AWS
- Innovated and created a health check tool with automatic remedy to effectively handle various common issues in customers' farms in SaaS platform using Python and Ansible

- Designed and implemented an automation to collect SaaS customers' daily license usages, calculate peak usage and report to a central hub enabling Sales and Customer Care teams to intrigue customers' engagement and satisfaction
- Handled issues & requirements from customers by trouble shooting, communication skills.

Senior Software Engineer, UFT R&D, Micro Focus, Shanghai, China Jun 2013 – Aug 2019 Technologies: C++, C#/WPF

- Added SAP NWBC support to the Unified Functional Testing tool in C++ enabling thousands of enterprise customers to leverage UFT's rich functionalities to perform automated test on SAP NWBC applications
- Innovated a new feature allowing UFT users to generate automation scripts by drag and drop from Object Spy Dialog
- Improved 50% the performance of UFT's Object Identification for web objects by refining the page learning algorithm
- Facelifted another sibling testing tool Sprinter by completely rewriting the UI in WPF

Software Engineer, AB Suite, Unisys, Shanghai, China Tashnalagian Chin MS SOI Samor

Aug 2010 – Jun 2013

Technologies: C++, MS SQL Server

• Developed new features and improved product quality by fixing defects in the core module

Software Engineer, JRD Communication Inc, Shanghai, China Jan 2009 – May 2010 Technologies: C++, Linux, MySQL, GDB, Valgrind debugging and profiling tool, UML

• Built an intermediate Linux daemon service serving as a bridge between various internet content providers and mobile phone users

Software Engineer, HiSoft, Shanghai, China

Apr 2008 – Dec 2008

Technologies: C++

• Worked as a Contingent Worker inside IBM to implement and test built-in commands in AIX

Junior Software Engineer, Neusoft, Shenyang, China

Jul 2006 - Mar 2008

Technologies: C/C++

AWARDS

Promoted to SaaS Expert due to excellence in work at Micro Focus in Jan 2021